Lisa Mabley

Senior Full-Stack Software Engineer

<u>lisamabley@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/lisamabley/</u>
Professional Website: <u>lisamabley.github.io</u>
GitHub: <u>https://github.com/LisaMabley</u>

Minneapolis, MN 55413

(612) 817-7516

PROFILE

Technical problem solver with 7 years of software engineering and full stack web development experience with *TypeScript, Node, PostgreSQL, React, Angular* and *GCP*. More than 10 years of experience wearing many hats in small/early-stage startups. Nimble and quick to learn new frameworks. Exceptional collaboration, mentoring, teamwork and communication skills.

EXPERIENCE

Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis MN - *Software Engineering Teaching Assistant* MAY 2023 - PRESENT (PART-TIME)

- Mentored two cohorts of students from no coding experience to entry-level software careers.
- Demonstrated logging, debugging and troubleshooting techniques.
- Eased learning friction and removed blockers to progress. Modeled growth mindset.

Cloudburst SBC, Minneapolis MN - Senior Full-Stack Software Developer

MAY 2018 - APRIL 2023

- Built and scaled a customer-facing mobile app and corporate CMS for a senior living company with thousands of users and dozens of properties around the country; Integrated an IoT platform with fleet-managed devices; Released mobile apps to the Google Play store and iOS App Store; Prototyped an Amazon Alexa skill. TypeScript, React, Angular, Node, PostgreSQL, GCP, Ionic
- Enhanced a half-million dollar yard care application project by adding estimation functionality and a subcontractor layer, reducing manual work. TypeScript, React, Supabase, Node, Next.js
- Established baseline data analytics and KPI numbers for a rapidly-growing telehealth client, revealing and correcting gaps in data collection. Created an admin dashboard to track and visualize employee performance and care standards for a large volume of patients.
 PostgreSQL, Big Query, Google Data Studio
- Optimized front- and back-end app performance via optimized queries, cached results, table
 pagination, search and sort to scale a training and compliance-focused client's applications from
 2,000 users to over 44,000 users; Released mobile apps to the Google Play store and iOS App
 Store. TypeScript, Angular, Node, Firebase, PostgreSQL, Ionic, Capacitor

 Created HIPAA-compliant logging system and client dashboard to track signup failures and abandons, allowing a healthcare client to optimize its account creation and health history input process, unlocking product improvements and onboarding insights. Sentry, Google Data Studio

ITM TwentyFirst, Minneapolis MN - Full-Stack Software Engineer

JUNE 2016 - MAY 2018

- Built a public-facing web app and API service for new customers to log in and confirm or update
 their contact information, saving the company significant costs by automating one time-consuming
 step of customer interaction. TypeScript, Angular, Node, SQL Server
- Synthesized large datasets and wrote complex queries, functions and stored procedures to isolate
 the financial products with the highest value, and provide clients with actionable information.

 Microsoft SQL Server
- Generated a dev dataset that accurately reflects production data patterns/volume using a Node app to obfuscate HIPAA-protected PII from production data. *TypeScript, Node, Angular, SQL Server*

SKILLS

- Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS, Java, Python, Lua
- Frameworks: Angular, Node.js, NestJS, React.js, Express, Next.js
- Databases: PostgreSQL, Cloud Firestore, mySQL, SQL Server
- Data Tools: Google Data Studio, Big Query
- Cloud Platforms: GCP, Supabase, Firebase, AWS, Heroku
- Mobile Tools: Ionic, Cordova, Capacitor
- Testing Tools: Playwright, Jasmine
- ORM: Prisma, TypeORM
- CI/CD: GitHub Actions
- Performance Monitoring: Sentry
- Dev Tools: GitHub, BitBucket, Jira, Docker, rpm, Yarn, Homebrew, Asana, Notion
- Creative: Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign)

EDUCATION

Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis, MN - Full Stack Software Engineering Certificate Completed an 18-week immersive program in full-stack software engineering.

Minneapolis College, Minneapolis, MN

Took semester courses in Python, Java, iOS development and Android development.

University of Minnesota – Twin Cities, Minneapolis, MN - Bachelor's Degree Completed a liberal arts bachelor's degree program with a major in art.